<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nic's notes - bible-project posts</title><link>https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project-rss.xml</link><description>Nic's notes - bible-project posts</description><atom:link href="https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project-rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><image><url>bitmoji.png</url><title>Nic's notes - bible-project posts</title><link>https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project-rss.xml</link></image><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 19:08:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shalom and Peace</title><link>https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project/shalom-and-peace</link><description>! In Hebrew the word is  References a complex situation with nothing missing Shalom can refer to a person To bring shalom is to make complete or restore In Prov</description><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bibleproject.com/bible-studies/shalom-peace/"&gt;study link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id="peace"&gt;Peace&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p&gt;generally means absnese of war&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Hebrew the word is &lt;code&gt;Shalom&lt;/code&gt; (Greek: Eirene). Basic biblical meeting ofShalom is "complete" or "whole". ie. a stone with no cracks, or stone wall withnogaps or missing grips&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;References a complex situation with nothing missing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shalom can refer to a person's well-being... Life is complex and when anythingis out of alignment our Shalom breaks down and needs to be restored&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To bring shalom is to make complete or restore&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Proverbs, to reconcile a broken relationship is to make shalom&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="isaiah"&gt;Isaiah&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Isaiah 9:6-7&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6 For a child will be born to us, a son will be given to us;And the government will rest on His shoulders;And His name will be called Wonderful Counselor, Mighty God,Eternal Father, Prince of Peace.7 There will be no end to the increase of His government or of peace,On the throne of David and over his kingdom,To establish it and to uphold it with justice and righteousnessFrom then on and forevermore.The zeal of the Lord of hosts will accomplish this. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id="jesus"&gt;Jesus&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jesus restores the broken relationship between humans and our creator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Scripture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 2:14-15&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jesus himeself is our &lt;em&gt;Eirene&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id="questions"&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prophet Isaiah looked forward to the arrival of a future king who wouldmake a covenant of shalom (peace, well-being) with his people. This kingwould set the world right and heal all that has been harmed. Read Isaiah9:6-7 aloud together. What specific words or phrases stand out to you asyou observe this passage and why?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Isaiah 9:6-7 6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a child will be born to us, a son will be given tous; And the government will rest on His shoulders; And His name will becalled Wonderful Counselor, Mighty God, Eternal Father, Prince of Peace.7There will be no end to the increase of His government or of peace, On thethrone of David and over his kingdom, To establish it and to uphold it withjustice and righteousness From then on and forevermore. The zeal of theLord of hosts will accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Words that stick out:     - child    - given to us    - government will rest    - no end to the increase    - zeal...will accomplish this&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prophet Isaiah looked forward to the arrival of the Prince of Peace, whosereign would lead to eternal shalom. Jesus’ arrival fulfilled Isaiah’s words.Read and reflect on Luke 2:9-15 as a group. Why do you think God announced theKing’s arrival to no-name shepherds? What does this tell you about the natureof God and his Kingdom?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Luke 2:9-15&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;9And an angel of the Lord suddenly stood before them, and the glory of theLord shone around them; and they were terribly frightened. 10But the angelsaid to them, “Do not be afraid; for behold, I bring you good news of greatjoy which will be for all the people; 11for today in the city of Davidthere has been born for you a Savior, who is Christ the Lord. 12This willbe a sign for you: you will find a baby wrapped in cloths and lying in amanger.” 13And suddenly there appeared with the angel a multitude of theheavenly host praising God and saying,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;14“Glory to God in the highest,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And on earth peace among men with whom He is pleased.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;15When the angels had gone away from them into heaven, the shepherds begansaying to one another, “Let us go straight to Bethlehem then, and see thisthing that has happened which the Lord has made known to us.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;At thsi point it seems obvious that the reason God came to the undesirablecompany of teh time was to illustrate that the Kingdom of Heaven was to be anupside down kingdom. Status and power are hinderences under Jesus' reign, so hebuilds his kingdom (from our perspective) from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biblical story shows how humanity often chooses a way of life apartfrom God and suffers as a result. According to Colossians 1:19-23 , whatdid God want to do to remedy this pain, and how did he accomplish hisdesire through Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Scripture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Colossians 1:19-23&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;19For it was the Father’s good pleasure for all the fullness to dwell inHim, 20and through Him to reconcile all things to Himself, having madepeace (εἰρηνοποιέω) through the blood of His cross; through Him, I say, whether things onearth or things in heaven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;21And although you were formerly alienated and hostile in mind, engaged inevil deeds, 22yet He has now reconciled you in His fleshly body throughdeath, in order to present you before Him holy and blameless and beyondreproach— 23if indeed you continue in the faith firmly established andsteadfast, and not moved away from the hope of the gospel that you haveheard, which was proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I,Paul, was made a minister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;God interacted with Creation as a created being himself, holding back&lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; in the person of Jesus. On our turf, God showed up to revive ourlifeless souls and call us to live as citizens in his kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jesus offers his peace to all people as a gift. Read Ephesians 2:11-16 .How did Jesus make peace between two sharply divided people groups (Jewsand Gentiles), and why did he do it (see Eph. 2:16)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Ephesians 2:11-16&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;11Therefore remember that formerly you, the Gentiles in the flesh, who arecalled “Uncircumcision” by the so-called “Circumcision,” which is performedin the flesh by human hands— 12remember that you were at that time separatefrom Christ, excluded from the commonwealth of Israel, and strangers to thecovenants of promise, having no hope and without God in the world. 13Butnow in Christ Jesus you who formerly were far off have been brought near bythe blood of Christ. 14For He Himself is our peace, who made both groupsinto one and broke down the barrier of the dividing wall, 15by abolishingin His flesh the enmity, which is the Law of commandments contained inordinances, so that in Himself He might make the two into one new man, thusestablishing peace, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;16and might reconcile them both in one body to Godthrough the cross, by it having put to death the enmity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jesus broke down the dividing wall of Circumcision by fulfilling Torah. Nolonger do the people of God need to be circumcized into the covenant (we havebaptism), and no longer are God's people separate from the world via outwardappearances but instead by living lives loyal to a different God - to Yahweh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition success"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jesus "put to death the enmity" by removing all &lt;em&gt;spiritually/covenantally relevant&lt;/em&gt; barriers that separated Jews from Gentiles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s carefully read Ephesians 4:1-3 How can humility, gentleness,patience, and love help maintain the unity Jesus calls his followers to?What happens to unity when one of these virtues is missing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Ephesians 4:1-3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1Therefore I, the prisoner of the Lord, implore you to walk in a mannerworthy of the calling with which you have been called, 2with all humilityand gentleness, with patience, showing tolerance for one another in love,3being diligent to preserve the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These things don't just help maintain unity - they are the postures of lifeJesus builds his Kingdom around (second to himself I suppose). Jesus levels theplaying field for all people, and no one has anymore right to anything thananyone else. Things like humility (right view of oneself), gentleness,patience, love, etc. are necessary for Jesus' kingdom to look how he wants itto look&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project/shalom-and-peace</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tree of Life</title><link>https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project/tree-of-life</link><description>Biblical story begins in a garden, which is presented as a type of Temple. The Moses meets God at a burning tree, a plant on a mountain radiating with God Jesus</description><content:encoded>&lt;h1 id="video"&gt;Video&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="eden"&gt;Eden&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Biblical story begins in a garden, which is presented as a type of Temple. Thetop (center) is the Tree of Life, which represents God's life and creativepower. Humans &lt;strong&gt;were supposed to eat from the Tree of Life&lt;/strong&gt; but there'sanother tree, the Tree of Knowledge of "good" and "bad" which representsassuming the authority to define good and bad for one's own life rather thantrusting God's defintion. Human eat of that tree and are thus exiled from thegarden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="burning-bush"&gt;Burning Bush&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moses meets God at a burning tree, a plant on a mountain radiating with God'spower just like the Tree of Life. Yahweh charges Moses to bring the same choiceto the Israelites that Adam and Eve had, which is to trust God or definemorality for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="jesus"&gt;Jesus&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jesus announced that God's eternal life is available through him now -originally in Eden given through the Tree of Life. Jesus invites other peopleto "eat of him" to be transformed by God's own life. The invitation is the same- to trust Yahweh or not. But Jesus' life exposes humanity's brokenness in that    humans crucified him. Jesus is hung on a cross (a tree) on the top of a    hill (like Mt. Sinai) and humans not only eat of a different false tree of    life, but they chopped down the real Tree of Life - Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id="questions"&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;1&lt;p&gt;What is one practical example of what it means to eat from the tree oflife? How is it different from eating from the false tree of life?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Giving money away I think is one practical example of eating from the tree oflife. Jesus calls us to share our blessings, and choosing to live by hisauthority rather than decide for myself what to do with my money (meaning tospend it on my desires only rather than invest in the Kingdom) then I make thesame choice humanity always makes - to not trust God's definition of good andbad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compare John 15:5-13with Matthew 7:15-20. How does the true vine give life? How do we recognize a false tree of life?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;John 15:5-13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5I am the vine, you are the branches; he who abides in Me and I in him, hebears much fruit, for apart from Me you can do nothing. 6If anyone does notabide in Me, he is thrown away as a branch and dries up; and they gatherthem, and cast them into the fire and they are burned. 7If you abide in Me,and My words abide in you, ask whatever you wish, and it will be done foryou. 8My Father is glorified by this, that you bear much fruit, and soprove to be My disciples. 9Just as the Father has loved Me, I have alsoloved you; abide in My love. 10If you keep My commandments, you will abidein My love; just as I have kept My Father’s commandments and abide in Hislove. 11These things I have spoken to you so that My joy may be in you, andthat your joy may be made full. Disciples’ Relation to Each Other 12“Thisis My commandment, that you love one another, just as I have loved you.13Greater love has no one than this, that one lay down his life for hisfriends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Matthew 7:15-20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;15“Beware of the false prophets, who come to you in sheep’s clothing, butinwardly are ravenous wolves. 16You will know them by their fruits. Grapesare not gathered from thorn bushes nor figs from thistles, are they? 17Soevery good tree bears good fruit, but the bad tree bears bad fruit. 18Agood tree cannot produce bad fruit, nor can a bad tree produce good fruit.19Every tree that does not bear good fruit is cut down and thrown into thefire. 20So then, you will know them by their fruits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The true vine gives life through communion and connection. Jesus says to "abidein [him]" which is represented by a choice to believe him about kingdom, love,relationships, brokenness, etc... By meditating on the Word of God, communingwith Jesus, being washed and guided by the Spirit we are transformed more and more intothe image of Jesus which is real and true life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are some examples of good fruit and bad fruit (see Galatians 5:16-25)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Galations 5:16-25&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;16But I say, walk by the Spirit, and you will not carry out the desire ofthe flesh. 17For the flesh sets its desire against the Spirit, and theSpirit against the flesh; for these are in opposition to one another, sothat you may not do the things that you please. 18But if you are led by theSpirit, you are not under the Law. 19Now the deeds of the flesh areevident, which are: immorality, impurity, sensuality, 20idolatry, sorcery,enmities, strife, jealousy, outbursts of anger, disputes, dissensions,factions, 21envying, drunkenness, carousing, and things like these, ofwhich I forewarn you, just as I have forewarned you, that those whopractice such things will not inherit the kingdom of God. 22But the fruitof the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness,faithfulness, 23gentleness, self-control; against such things there is nolaw. 24Now those who belong to Christ Jesus have crucified the flesh withits passions and desires. 25If we live by the Spirit, let us also walk bythe Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good fruit:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;- choosing to guard my eyes and thoughts against sexual immorality- remaining calm when things aren&amp;#39;t going my way at work- drinking water instead of _another_ drink at night- giving money away out of love- seeking unity and charity especially in any time of conflict&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bad fruit:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;outbursts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;work&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;basically&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;giving&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;up&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;hope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;someone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;successful&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;s grace I have a desire to help peopl learn and succeed, but I can exhaust that desire and instead of prioritize an individual&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;well&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;growth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;frustration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;above&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;annoyance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;guide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;than&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;spirit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;teaching&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;gentleness&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;having&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;second&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;third&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;drink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are led byt he Spirit, you are not under the Law... This isn't sayingthat the Law doesn't apply, but that by the Spirit's guidance we will neverbe found guilty by anything in the Law!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Jesus talks about what his death will accomplish, he talks about aseed going into the ground before it bears fruit (see John 12:23-26). Whatcould it look like to live in the ways of Jesus and bear the fruit of life?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;John 12:23-26&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;23And Jesus *answered them, saying, “The hour has come for the Son of Manto be glorified. 24Truly, truly, I say to you, unless a grain of wheatfalls into the earth and dies, it remains alone; but if it dies, it bearsmuch fruit. 25He who loves his life loses it, and he who hates his life inthis world will keep it to life eternal. 26If anyone serves Me, he mustfollow Me; and where I am, there My servant will be also; if anyone servesMe, the Father will honor him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meditating on God's faithfulness to humanity in spite of our disobedience Ithink is an avenue by which the Spirit changes our hearts and as we are changedby him we live lives that reflect Jesus' own life&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think there can be many facets to the seed dying aspect, one relevant pieceseems fairly self-evident in the passage... if we hold onto our life (ie. be aseed that never dies) then we will never flourish, but if we give up the lifewe have now and live like Jesus did, we will blessed with life&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project/tree-of-life</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abraham and Melchizedek</title><link>https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project/abraham-and-melchizedek</link><description>God creates Eden in which he places humans to be his royal image - priests. God God chooses Abraham and Sarah as the first royal priesthood as they are chosen A</description><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bibleproject.com/bible-studies/abraham-and-melchizedek/"&gt;link to study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id="video"&gt;Video&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="priests"&gt;Priests&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;God creates Eden in which he places humans to be his royal image - priests. Godsets humans up to receive his blessing but humans choose their own way. Thepromise is for a priest and a sacrifice to come in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;God chooses Abraham and Sarah as the first royal priesthood as they are chosenby God to bless all the nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="melchizedek"&gt;Melchizedek&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A priestly king of Salem. Melchizedek recognizes Yahweh as the God of gods -Abraham tithes to him and that's about the end of the story&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salem is ancient short name for Jerusalem. Abraham's tithe to Melchizedek is just like the Israelite call to tithe to theLevites (priests) to support them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="royal-family"&gt;Royal Family&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abraham and Sarah are promised their own children but they take amtters intotheir own hands by scheming with Hagar. Eventually Sarah is given her own son,Issac, who God then calls for his life as a test of Abraham - it represents Godchallenging Abraham to trust him with his own promise, and to not go his ownway with Sarah&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DUring the Isaac sacrifice narrative a ram is given in place and Abraham names the place "God will provide".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="types"&gt;Types&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story of God's call to sacrifice Isaac is much like the story of Abrahammeeting Melchizedek. In the Melchizedek story Abraham meets a priest on a highplace and gives him an offering. In the Isaac story Abraham acts as the priestand a ram is given to him by the LORD that covers the sins of Abraham's family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Atonement and Covering&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Covering the sin in this case looks much more like redemption and resolverather than payment for gult, similar to a small-scale apology can cover agrievance even though no payment is made to make anything 'right', the'covering' is simply a sign of forgiveness&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id="questions"&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shalem, or Salem, is later known as Jerusalem. Moriah, a mountainous region inJerusalem, is later called the “mount of the LORD” (Genesis 22:14) and the“temple mount” (2 Chronicles 3:1). With all of this in mind, compare Genesis14:17-20 with Genesis 22:1-14 . How do you see God providing for Abraham inthese similar settings?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Genesis 22:14&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;14Abraham called the name of that place The Lord Will Provide, as it issaid to this day, “In the mount of the Lord it will be provided.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;2 Chronicles 3:1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Temple Construction in Jerusalem&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1Then Solomon began to build the house of the Lord in Jerusalem on MountMoriah, where the Lord had appeared to his father David, at the place thatDavid had prepared on the threshing floor of Ornan the Jebusite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Genesis 14:17-20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;God’s Promise to Abram&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;17Then after his return from the defeat of Chedorlaomer and the kings whowere with him, the king of Sodom went out to meet him at the valley ofShaveh (that is, the King’s Valley). 18And Melchizedek king of Salembrought out bread and wine; now he was a priest of God Most High. 19Heblessed him and said,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Blessed be Abram of God Most High,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Possessor of heaven and earth;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;20And blessed be God Most High,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who has delivered your enemies into your hand.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He gave him a tenth of all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Genesis 22:1-14&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Offering of Isaac&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1Now it came about after these things, that God tested Abraham, and said tohim, “Abraham!” And he said, “Here I am.” 2He said, “Take now your son,your only son, whom you love, Isaac, and go to the land of Moriah, andoffer him there as a burnt offering on one of the mountains of which I willtell you.” 3So Abraham rose early in the morning and saddled his donkey,and took two of his young men with him and Isaac his son; and he split woodfor the burnt offering, and arose and went to the place of which God hadtold him. 4On the third day Abraham raised his eyes and saw the place froma distance. 5Abraham said to his young men, “Stay here with the donkey, andI and the lad will go over there; and we will worship and return to you.”6Abraham took the wood of the burnt offering and laid it on Isaac his son,and he took in his hand the fire and the knife. So the two of them walkedon together. 7Isaac spoke to Abraham his father and said, “My father!” Andhe said, “Here I am, my son.” And he said, “Behold, the fire and the wood,but where is the lamb for the burnt offering?” 8Abraham said, “God willprovide for Himself the lamb for the burnt offering, my son.” So the two ofthem walked on together. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;9Then they came to the place of which God had toldhim; and Abraham built the altar there and arranged the wood, and bound hisson Isaac and laid him on the altar, on top of the wood. 10Abrahamstretched out his hand and took the knife to slay his son. 11But the angelof the Lord called to him from heaven and said, “Abraham, Abraham!” And hesaid, “Here I am.” 12He said, “Do not stretch out your hand against thelad, and do nothing to him; for now I know that you fear God, since youhave not withheld your son, your only son, from Me.” 13Then Abraham raisedhis eyes and looked, and behold, behind him a ram caught in the thicket byhis horns; and Abraham went and took the ram and offered him up for a burntoffering in the place of his son. 14Abraham called the name of that placeThe Lord Will Provide, as it is said to this day, “In the mount of the Lordit will be provided.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition success"&gt;&lt;p&gt;5Abraham said to his young men, “Stay here with the donkey, and I and thelad will go over there; and we will worship and return to you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Genesis 14&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Genesis 22&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Melchizedek provides bread and wine&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yahweh provides the ram&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yahweh gave Abram victory over Chedorlaomer&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yahweh gave Abraham Isaac's safety&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you review Hebrews 7 , notice how the author assures their audience thatJesus is better than any other priest. What are some of the reasons theauthor provides? How is this good news for everyone?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Hebrews 7&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Melchizedek’s Priesthood Like Christ’s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1For this Melchizedek, king of Salem, priest of the Most High God, who met Abraham as he was returning from the slaughter of the kings and blessed him, 2to whom also Abraham apportioned a tenth part of all the spoils, was first of all, by the translation of his name, king of righteousness, and then also king of Salem, which is king of peace. 3Without father, without mother, without genealogy, having neither beginning of days nor end of life, but made like the Son of God, he remains a priest perpetually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4Now observe how great this man was to whom Abraham, the patriarch, gave a tenth of the choicest spoils. 5And those indeed of the sons of Levi who receive the priest’s office have commandment in the Law to collect a tenth from the people, that is, from their brethren, although these are descended from Abraham. 6But the one whose genealogy is not traced from them collected a tenth from Abraham and blessed the one who had the promises. 7But without any dispute the lesser is blessed by the greater. 8In this case mortal men receive tithes, but in that case one receives them, of whom it is witnessed that he lives on. 9And, so to speak, through Abraham even Levi, who received tithes, paid tithes, 10for he was still in the loins of his father when Melchizedek met him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;11Now if perfection was through the Levitical priesthood (for on the basis of it the people received the Law), what further need was there for another priest to arise according to the order of Melchizedek, and not be designated according to the order of Aaron? 12For when the priesthood is changed, of necessity there takes place a change of law also. 13For the one concerning whom these things are spoken belongs to another tribe, from which no one has officiated at the altar. 14For it is evident that our Lord was descended from Judah, a tribe with reference to which Moses spoke nothing concerning priests. 15And this is clearer still, if another priest arises according to the likeness of Melchizedek, 16who has become such not on the basis of a law of physical requirement, but according to the power of an indestructible life. 17For it is attested of Him,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You are a priest forever&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the order of Melchizedek.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;18For, on the one hand, there is a setting aside of a former commandment because of its weakness and uselessness 19(for the Law made nothing perfect), and on the other hand there is a bringing in of a better hope, through which we draw near to God. 20And inasmuch as it was not without an oath 21(for they indeed became priests without an oath, but He with an oath through the One who said to Him,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Lord has sworn&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And will not change His mind,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‘You are a priest forever’ ”);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;22so much the more also Jesus has become the guarantee of a better covenant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;23The former priests, on the one hand, existed in greater numbers because they were prevented by death from continuing, 24but Jesus, on the other hand, because He continues forever, holds His priesthood permanently. 25Therefore He is able also to save forever those who draw near to God through Him, since He always lives to make intercession for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;26For it was fitting for us to have such a high priest, holy, innocent, undefiled, separated from sinners and exalted above the heavens; 27who does not need daily, like those high priests, to offer up sacrifices, first for His own sins and then for the sins of the people, because this He did once for all when He offered up Himself. 28For the Law appoints men as high priests who are weak, but the word of the oath, which came after the Law, appoints a Son, made perfect forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Melchizedek was "king of righteousness" and "kind of peace", Jesus is a priest according to "the order of Melchizedek" and so seems to be that Jesus is the continued reigning king of righteousness and peace&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Melchizedek was priest of God Most High - the priestly order changed to Levi with the giving of the Law... Jesus represents, and &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;, another change in the priesthood which necessitates another change in law (verse 12). Jesus' kingship and priesthood is more similar to Melchizek's than Levi's (who was no king anyways).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Levitical priesthood was not bound by an oath - but Jesus' priesthood is bound by Yahweh's oath to not change his mind, Jesus is priest forever&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Former priests, Levites, changed due to death, but Jesus persists forever (Melchizedek also presumably died)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project/abraham-and-melchizedek</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chara-Joy</title><link>https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project/chara-joy</link><description>There are several words for similar feelings - example like  Genesis tells us creation and life bring joy Bible shows us that humanity and brokenness mark our w</description><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bibleprojectz.com/bible-studies/chara-joy/"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id="chara-joy"&gt;Chara / Joy&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several words for similar feelings - example like &lt;code&gt;joy&lt;/code&gt; has several synonyms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="sources"&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Genesis tells us creation and life bring joyPsalm 104 - A good bottle of wine is God's gift to bring joy to people's heartsP#lm 65 - Beautiful things bring joyJeremiah 33:11 - Weddings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="corruption"&gt;Corruption&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bible shows us that humanity and brokenness mark our world by death and loss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="joy-in-spite-of-corruption"&gt;Joy in spite of corruption&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;God's people have reasons in God's faithfulness to be joyful. Joy in the LORD is not determinmed by current struggles, but by future hope and deliverance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="jesus"&gt;Jesus&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;His birth gives good news and brings great joy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5 - Jesus says to rejoice and be glad when we are persecuted for his Name&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="apostles"&gt;Apostles&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul says he chooses joy when he is in jail&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joy is a &lt;em&gt;choice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 6:10 -&amp;gt; Paul is filled with sorrow and yet rejoicing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition success"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Christian joy is rooted in future hope and expectation of a Messiah, ofJesus, to come again. It is a profound choice, not the result of currentcircumstances&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id="questions"&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Israelites choose a path apart from God. As a result, they get exiledfrom their land and dominated by foreign nations. But the prophet Isaiahknew that sorrow would not have the final word with these people. He lookedforward to the day when Yahweh would end pain and corruption to lead theminto endless, joyful living. Read Isaiah 49:13 and Isaiah 51:11 . What doesIsaiah tell us about God’s character in these passages? What does Isaiahsay will happen to God’s people?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Isaiah 49:13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;13Shout for joy, O heavens! And rejoice, O earth!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Break forth into joyful shouting, O mountains!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the Lord has comforted His people&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And will have compassion on His afflicted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Isaiah 51:11&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;11So the ransomed of the Lord will return&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And come with joyful shouting to Zion,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And everlasting joy will be on their heads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They will obtain gladness and joy,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And sorrow and sighing will flee away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isiah tells us that God is good and faithful. He mentions God's pastfaithfulness - &lt;code&gt;For the Lord _has_ comforted His people&lt;/code&gt; as well as futurefaithfulness - &lt;code&gt;So the randomed of the Lord _will_ return...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isiah leans in on Yahweh's defining nature from Exodus 34:6. God's &lt;code&gt;hesed&lt;/code&gt;, his&lt;strong&gt;steadfase love&lt;/strong&gt;, is what is our hope. Otherwise our God is no different thanany powerful but fickle diety. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isiah also doesn't, in these short passages, promise or claim a promise of anykind of temporal happiness - the joy is historical-facing in reflecting onGod's deliverance and future-facing inr reflecting also on God's deliverance.God's people were still supposed to find this joy in the midst of their bondage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prophet Isaiah looked forward to the coming of Israel’s redeemer. Hisprophecies were fulfilled with the arrival of Jesus. Read Luke 2:9-11 . Whywere the shepherds afraid? What reasons did the angels give for them torejoice instead?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Luke 2:9-11&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;9And an angel of the Lord suddenly stood before them, and the glory of theLord shone around them; and they were terribly frightened. 10But the angelsaid to them, “Do not be afraid; for behold, I bring you good news of greatjoy which will be for all the people; 11for today in the city of Davidthere has been born for you a Savior, who is Christ the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Presumably the shepherds were afraid because of &lt;code&gt;the glory of the Lord&lt;/code&gt;. Allthroughout the OT we have examples of God's people fearing this glory,specifically on Sinai. Yahweh even tells Moses that he can only be shownYahweh's back due to his glory, and then Moses has to veil his face so that theglory of the Lord persisted on him would not terrify the Israelites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The angels outright said that a Savior has been born, the Messiah has come.There is no greater cause for joy than the king of creation returning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joy can persist in the harshest of circumstances because it depends on Godand his promises. Read Matthew 5:11-12 , Acts 13:50-52 , and Hebrews 12:1-3. According to these passages, what specific truths about God can sustainjoy even through painful or dire situations?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition success"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joy can persist in the harshest of circumstances because it depends on Godand his promises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Matthew 5:11-12&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;11“Blessed are you when people insult you and persecute you, and falselysay all kinds of evil against you because of Me. 12Rejoice and be glad, foryour reward in heaven is great; for in the same way they persecuted theprophets who were before you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Acts 13:50-52&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;50But the Jews incited the devout women of prominence and the leading menof the city, and instigated a persecution against Paul and Barnabas, anddrove them out of their district. 51But they shook off the dust of theirfeet in protest against them and went to Iconium. 52And the disciples werecontinually filled with joy and with the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Hebrews 12:1-3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jesus, the Example&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1Therefore, since we have so great a cloud of witnesses surrounding us, letus also lay aside every encumbrance and the sin which so easily entanglesus, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us, 2fixingour eyes on Jesus, the author and perfecter of faith, who for the joy setbefore Him endured the cross, despising the shame, and has sat down at theright hand of the throne of God. 3For consider Him who has endured suchhostility by sinners against Himself, so that you will not grow weary andlose heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harsh treatment of us, particularly for faith, reflects Jesus' life. We standwith God-incarnate in living for a different kingdom which has negativeconsequences for us in the modern age, but obviously not in God's age that'salready here and yet coming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holy Spirit gives us joy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have long list of people in history who lived faithful lives, struggled   with God, experienced pain, and yet were faithful the Lord by God's own   grace. Similarly we are chosen and favored - the receipients of God's   &lt;code&gt;hesed&lt;/code&gt; love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we see how Jesus’ loving way of life has overcome death itself, joystarts to become strangely reasonable. But this doesn’t mean it is wise toignore or suppress sorrow. Read 2 Corinthians 6:3-10 . How did Paulintegrate both joy and sorrow?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="admonition scripture"&gt;&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;2 Corinthians 6:3-10&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3giving no cause for offense in anything, so that the ministry will not bediscredited, 4but in everything commending ourselves as servants of God, inmuch endurance, in afflictions, in hardships, in distresses, 5in beatings,in imprisonments, in tumults, in labors, in sleeplessness, in hunger, 6inpurity, in knowledge, in patience, in kindness, in the Holy Spirit, ingenuine love, 7in the word of truth, in the power of God; by the weapons ofrighteousness for the right hand and the left, 8by glory and dishonor, byevil report and good report; regarded as deceivers and yet true; 9asunknown yet well-known, as dying yet behold, we live; as punished yet notput to death, 10as sorrowful yet always rejoicing, as poor yet making manyrich, as having nothing yet possessing all things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="false">https://pypeaday.github.io/small-group-notes//bible-project/chara-joy</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>